Love actually is all around.
Love Actually is a comedy, romance, drama film directed by Richard Curtis.
Eight very different couples deal with their love lives in various loosely
interrelated tales all set during a frantic month before Christmas in London.
The Prime Minister, played by Hugh Grant.
Harry, played by Alan Rickman.
Karen, played by Emma Thompson.
Daniel, played by Liam Neeson.
Natalie, played by Martine McCutcheon.
Jamie Bennett, played by Colin Firth.
Love Actually is a 2003 Christmas romantic comedy film
written and directed by Richard Curtis.
The film features an ensemble cast, composed predominantly of British
actors, many of whom had worked with Curtis in previous projects.
An international co-production of the United Kingdom, United States
and France, it was mostly filmed on location in London.
The film delves into different aspects of love as shown through 10 separate stories involving a
variety of individuals, many of whom are interlinked as the plot progresses.
The story begins five weeks before Christmas and is played out in a weekly countdown
until the holiday, followed by an epilogue that takes place in the New Year.
The film, Curtis's first as director, was released in the US on 14 November
2003 and a week later in the UK during its theatrical run.
Love Actually was a box-office success, grossing $250.2
million worldwide on a budget of $40–45 million.
The film received mixed reviews and a nomination for the Golden Globe
Award for Best Motion Picture – Musical or Comedy.
In recent years, it has developed a cult following, and is often a staple film shown
during the Christmas period in both the United Kingdom and United States.
A made-for-television short sequel, Red Nose Day Actually, aired in two different versions on
BBC One and NBC in 2017, as part of the fundraising event Red Nose Day 2017.
The film explores themes of london, england, usa president, rock
star, school performance, love at first sight.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.